################ this is a short tutorial on how to use Git & GitHub ################

git add <filename to add> --- command to track file in Git 

the commit is a record of what files are to be tracked. With the add command we track them by adding them to the staging area, while with the "commit" we commit them.

E.g. : git commit -m "Your message about the commit" example how to commit

git checkout -b <my branch name> --- this command will automatically create a new branch and hten check you out on it.

git branch --- this command confirms that the branch which was just created. 

 If  switched back to the master branch and changes are made with some more commits, your new branch won't see any of those changes until the merge of those changes to the  new branch.

ref site: https://product.hubspot.com/blog/git-and-github-tutorial-for-beginners
